Charles Renk

Supportive web developer with detailed knowledge of agency industry practices and skills to provide long-term success for client-focused companies. Trained for full stack web development with most of my experience in front end development. Known for goal-oriented mindset and strategic thinking.

2016 Aldrich Ave S Minneapolis, MN 55405 (262)287-8299 charleswrenk@gmail.com www.charlesrenk.com

EXPERIENCE

Propoint Global (Contractor), Minneapolis, MN — *Appcelerator Developer*

February 2020 - Current

Developed mobile applications for a SaaS for hair salons

Used Appcelerator Studio and Titanium to develop both Android and IOS versions of phone apps

Remotely collaborated on projects through Atlassian and Microsoft 365

Implemented web standards for both Google Play store and App Store Connect in order to publish applications.

Periscope, Minneapolis, MN

January 2018 - March 2020

— Associate Developer

June 2018 - March 2020

Produced websites compatible with multiple browsers

Pinpointed user experience issues to devise targeted suggestions for creating cohesive user experience

Designed and updated layouts to meet usability and performance requirements

Created eye catching and functional digital design concepts across various platforms to strengthen company brand and identity

Used programming capabilities in PHP, SQL and JavaScript and other libraries as needed

Collaborated with in-house web designers to create sleek and innovative UI design

Represented web team at meetings with clients and discussed project goals and milestones

— Web Developer Intern

January 2018 - June 2018

Built and maintained websites for various clients in a variety CMS environments

SKILLS

Front End Development

Wordpress Development

Full Stack Development

Content Management

Systems

HTML Email Development

SOFTWARE

JavaScript

HTML5

CSS3

Bootstrap

SQL

Mongo

NodeJS

ExpressJS

JQuery

Wordpress

WP: Advanced Custom Fields

PHP

AngularJS

React

Redux

AEM

Alexa Development

DialogFlow

Implemented web components across new and existing designs Collaborated with product managers, testers, and developers to initiate process improvements

Researched and developed new technology designs Attended corporate learning and development programs to gain competencies and professional skills

Developed user interfaces with modern JavaScript frameworks, HTML5 and CSS3

Utilized scripting languages, content creation tools, management tools, and digital media to design web sites

Prime Digital Academy, Minneapolis, MN — Full Stack Software Engineering Student

June 2017 - October 2017

Planned and engineered RESTful web services to manipulate dynamic datasets

Established milestones for projects and worked with all team members to meet deadlines

Created site layout and user interface using HTML and CSS practices

Researched new technologies, software packages and hardware products for use in website projects

Developed, coded and updated full stack websites using a variety of tech including: Mongo, SQL, NodeJS, Angular JS, and Express

EDUCATION

University of Minnesota: Twin Cities, Minneapolis/St. Paul —Bachelor of Arts: Music

September 2012 - May 2016

Prime Digital Academy, Minneapolis, MN — Full Stack Engineering Certification

June 2017 - October 2017

SOFTWARE CONT.

HTML Emails

Mail Chimp

WP Engine

AWS: EC2

AWS: s3

AWS: Lambda

Appcelerator Studio

Grunt

Webpack